bowflexhomegyms.com 2016-12-04

# Privacy Policy | Bowflex

The Nautilus, Inc. family of Web Sites (NautilusInc.com, Nautilus.com, Bowflex.com, BowflexInternational.com, Bowflex.eu, SchwinnFitness.com, UniversalHomeFitness.com, and BowflexFriends.com) ("Sites") takes the protection and proper use of your personal information seriously. We respect your privacy, and take care to safeguard information in our possession.

The privacy practices of this statement apply to our services available under the domains and subdomains of Nautilus, Inc.. By visiting this or any or our Sites you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree please do not use or access our Sites. As this policy may be modified from time-to-time, you should check this Privacy Policy frequently for any such changes. Your continued access or use of our Sites shall constitute acceptance of any modifications of the Privacy Policy. Our use of information gathered or obtained at any time is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time of such use.

This Privacy Policy describes the information, as part of the normal operation of our services, we collect from you and what may happen to that information. Although this Privacy Policy may seem long, we have prepared a detailed policy because we believe you should know as much as possible about our practices so that you can make informed decisions. By accepting the Terms of Use, visiting any of our Sites, shopping on any of our Sites, completing our surveys, participating in our sweepstakes or other incentives, responding to our e-mails, or otherwise interacting with Nautilus, Inc., you are consenting to Nautilus, Inc. practices, including the use and disclosure of any personally identifiable information you have shared with us, as described in this Privacy Policy. Finally, please note that this policy applies only to Nautilus, Inc. family of Web Sites and not to other companies' or organizations' Web sites to which we link.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the Site, please contact us by:

  * Sending an e-mail to privacy@nautilus.com
  * Sending a written request to the following address:

Nautilus, Inc. Attn: Customer Service  
17750 SE 6th Way   
Vancouver, WA 98683

#### A SPECIAL NOTE ABOUT CHILDREN

Our Sites are not designed or intended for use by children under 13 and comply with the provisions of the Children's On-Line Privacy Protection Act. If you are under 18, you should use our Sites only with involvement of a parent or guardian. Children under 13 may not submit any personally identifiable information to us, and if we discover that we have inadvertently gathered any such information from a child under 13, we will take appropriate steps to delete it.

#### WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DOES NAUTILUS, INC. GATHER?

The information we obtain from shoppers helps us personalize and continually improve your shopping experience at our Sites. Here are the general types of information we gather:

#### INFORMATION YOU GIVE US

We receive and store any information you provide to us when you complete surveys, request additional information from us, participate in a sweepstakes or other incentives, post information on our Sites, make purchases online, set up accounts, sign up to receive our newsletters or other e-mail communications, communicate by e-mail, telephone or physical mail with our customer service, or otherwise interact with us. Such information may include your name, address, e-mail address, shopping interests and preferences, transaction history, and other personal data ("Personal Information"). We collect Personal Information that is reasonably necessary to comply with your requests and with our legitimate business interests. You can choose not to provide certain information, but then you might not be able to participate in our surveys or incentives, purchase products, or take advantage of certain useful Site features.

#### INFORMATION GATHERED AUTOMATICALLY

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many Web sites, we use "cookies" and "clear gifs" to obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses one of our Sites, or when you are provided the opportunity to complete surveys, participate in a sweepstakes or other incentives, or open or respond to any newsletter or other e-mail you may have requested.

Briefly, "cookies" are small files that we transfer to your computer's hard drive or your Web browser memory to enable our systems to recognize your browser and to provide convenience and other features to you, such as recognizing you as an existing customer or previous Site visitor. "Clear gifs" are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and may be used to track the online movements of Web users or to let us know if you have opened an e-mail that we sent you.

Examples of the information we collect and analyze in this manner include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; computer and connection information such as browser type and version, operating system, and platform; your behavior on our Web site and related services, including the products you view or searched for, as well as the URL you come from and go to next (whether this URL is on our site or not). The cookies and clear gifs that we use do not contain and are not tied to personally identifiable information about you.

You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although in that case you may not be able to participate in our surveys or incentives, purchase products, or take advantage of certain useful Site features.

#### HOW WE USE PERSONAL INFORMATION

Information about Site shoppers and other users is an important part of our business and we take steps to maintain the privacy and security of such information against unauthorized access. We generally use such information for such purposes as customizing future shopping and savings opportunities for you, improving our services, and communicating with you if you have authorized such communication.

From time to time, we make our mailing list (names and addresses only) and general shopping activity available to carefully screened companies whose products or services we believe will be of interest to you and whose privacy practices meet the Direct Marketing Association’s privacy standards. We do not share email addresses for this purpose. If you do not want to receive mailings from other reputable companies and prefer that we do not share any information with these companies, please send an email to privacy@nautilus.com.

#### AGGREGATED RESEARCH DATA

We produce research reports and other information and data about online shopping. Such information and data is based upon aggregated, anonymous information about hundreds of thousands of online shoppers and does not include personally identifiable information about individuals.

#### AGENTS

From time to time, we employ other companies and individuals to perform various functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, providing search results and links (including paid listings and links), processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.

#### ONLINE FINANCING

If you apply for credit on the Sites, your Personal Information may be shared with a credit agency(ies) and other parties as necessary for our business purposes in connection with such credit application. All credit decisions are subject to the policies set forth in the credit application.

#### OTHER CORPORATE ENTITIES

We share much of our data, including personal information about you, with our subsidiaries and joint ventures that are committed to serving you throughout the world. To the extent that these entities have access to your information, they will treat it at least as protectively as they treat information they obtain from their other users. Our subsidiaries and joint ventures follow privacy practices no less protective of all users than our practices described in this document, to the extent allowed by applicable law.

#### BUSINESS TRANSACTIONS

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy stores, subsidiaries, or business units. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets but remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Notice (unless, of course, the customer consents otherwise as described above). Also, in the unlikely event that Nautilus, Inc. or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets.

#### PROTECTION OF NAUTILUS, INC. AND OTHERS

We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with law; enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements; assist in fraud protection or investigation; or protect the rights, property, or security of Nautilus, Inc., our users, or others. Nautilus, Inc. cooperates with law enforcement inquiries, as well as other third parties to enforce laws. Therefore, in response to a verified and legitimate request by law enforcement or other government officials relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity, we can (and you authorize us to) disclose your name, city, state, telephone number, e-mail address and other information without a subpoena. Without limiting the above, in an effort to respect your privacy and comply with our obligation as a good corporate citizen , we will not otherwise disclose your personal information to law enforcement or other government officials without a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure, except when we believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to: prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss; or report suspected illegal activity.

Due to the existing regulatory and legal environment, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. By way of example (without limiting the foregoing), we may be required to disclose personal information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Therefore, although we use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private.

#### HOW SECURE IS INFORMATION ABOUT ME?

We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. We also use a secure server hosting location, firewall protection and controlled access to protect your data. All transmissions between our secured server and our corporate computer systems are done through private networks rather than through the Internet. We also have reasonable security measures in place to protect against loss, misuse and alteration of your information under our control. While no system is completely foolproof, we take the security of your personal information seriously, and our security measures are designed to protect that information in a responsible manner. However, you should be aware that any communication via the Internet, and security measures in connection with such communication, is not failsafe or foolproof, and there is always a possibility that data may be lost or intercepted by unauthorized parties during such transmission or after receipt. You agree that Nautilus, Inc. shall have no liability whatsoever in connection with such lost or intercepted data.

#### E-MAIL POLICIES

From time to time, Nautilus, Inc. will send newsletters and other e-mail to members and others. You can always choose not to receive e-mail from Nautilus, Inc.. Each of our e-mail messages contains a link or instructions at the bottom of the e-mail for the purpose of adjusting your e-mail subscription preferences. If you do not want to receive e-mail from us, please follow the instructions in any e-mail you receive or in the "Opt-Out" section below to contact us and be removed from our e-mailing list.

#### ANTI-SPAM POLICY

Nautilus, Inc. is opposed to unsolicited commercial e-mail ("spam"). If you receive any unsolicited e-mails from spammers, please be assured that Nautilus, Inc. did not provide your e-mail address to such parties.

This does not mean that we can prevent spam from happening on the Internet. Unfortunately, spammers obtain e-mail addresses in a number of devious ways, including when you respond and ask to be taken off a spam e-mail list, and in some cases by just generating e-mails to millions of random e-mail addresses in the hopes of getting a few "live" ones.

If you believe that you have received unsolicited e-mail from us, please contact privacy@nautilus.com

#### REVISIONS

Your contacts with Nautilus, Inc. and use of Nautilus, Inc. services are subject to this Privacy Notice. Since our business changes constantly, this Privacy Policy will also change from time to time. You should also check for recent changes on our Web site or other services whenever you visit.

#### WHAT CHOICES DO I HAVE?

As discussed above, you can always choose not to provide information, although that might prevent us from personalizing our services for you or may prevent you from participating in a survey or sweepstakes or taking advantage of certain useful Site features. We will retain in our files information you have requested to delete in some circumstances, such as to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our Terms of Use. Furthermore, such prior information is never completely removed from our databases due to technical and legal constraints, including stored "back up" systems.

#### OPT-OUT

If you do not want to receive informational or promotional information from us via phone, e-mail or mail, or want to review, delete, change or modify any of your Personal Information, you may do so by:

  * Sending an e-mail to privacy@nautilus.com
  * Sending a written request to the following address:

Nautilus, Inc. Attn: Customer Service  
17750 SE 6th Way  
Vancouver, WA 98683

If you do not want Nautilus, Inc. to share information we collect or receive about you, please contact us via e-mail at privacy@nautilus.com. Please include your name and mailing address in the message.

Please make sure to clearly indicate your contact and data privacy preferences by product line. Also, please include the e-mail address you used when you registered with the Site and/or provided the information to help us verify your request.

You may notify us about your preferences at any time. Your request will remain in effect until you notify us otherwise. We will honor your request and not share the information we collect about you, except as permitted by law. If you are an existing customer, please understand that you may continue to receive marketing offers directly from other companies that were already in production prior to the processing of your request.

This Privacy Notice was last modified on October 19, 2009.
